拿走苹果 谢尔曼老师!
Take the apple, Mrs. Sherman!
12月19日
上午 9:01
"苹果尊师"策略适得其反
- 手伸出来 拿着 - 瑞安先生
- Reach out and take it. Take the apple. - Mr. Ryan.
距新罕布什尔州特别国会选举还有2天
瑞安先生 请你退回演讲台
Mr. Ryan, would you please step back to your podium?
她不拿苹果
She wouldn't take the apple.
你们哪个
Which one of you Johnny
脑子进水想出这么个点子来
Appledick shit for brains came up with that bit?
夫人 我刚到这个冰与火搅屎棍之歌的地方
Hi, ma'am, I just arrived here in Winter Blunderland.
他看起来就像给蒂娜递点心的艾克·特纳[美国已故歌手因虐妻离婚 蒂娜为其前妻]
He looked like Ike Turner handing Tina a snack.
关键问题是
I think we've identified the key problem,
乔纳没办法与人类正常相处
which is that Jonah does not interact well with humans.
不 我是没法和丑贱老太婆相处
No, I don't interact well with hag-ass old bitches.
你刚刚把新罕布什尔州铐在暖气片上
Do you realize that you just handed O'Brien New Hampshire
洗干净剃好阴毛拱手送给了奥布莱恩
chained to a radiator with its twat shaved?
- 挂了 - 妈 消消气
- I'm hanging up! - I'm sorry, Mom.
好的地方就是
You know what? On the positive side,
现在我可以专心于我们的家庭周末了
now I can just try and concentrate on our little family weekend.
- 只有我们梅耶家的人  - 那为什么盖瑞在这
- Just us Meyers. - Well, then why is Gary here?
- 不好意思 - 盖瑞也是家人
- I mean, no offense. - Gary's family, too.
- 谢谢 - 我很激动你和爸爸 还有莫莫
- Oh, thank you. - I'm just really excited to have this time
能有机会了解真正的马乔里
for you and Dad and Monnie to get to know the real Marjorie.
好玩的马乔里 不是平常的特工马乔里
I mean, fun Marjorie, not just Marjorie the Secret Service agent.
能了解好玩有趣的马乔里我也很激动
Oh, I'm excited to get to know fun Marjorie, too.
那她什么时候来啊
When is she arriving?
开玩笑 只是玩笑
I'm just kidding. I'm just teasing.
大卫营 马里兰州
上午 9:40
总统在开车
The president is driving.
小心
Look out.
怎么样
How about that?
- 看 - 爸爸 莫莫
- Look! - Dad! Monny!
- 凯瑟琳小猫猫  - 好的
- Kitty Cat! - All right,
中国人随时会来
so the Chinese are gonna be here any minute.
- 对 - 中国政府要求完全保密
- Yeah. - Beijing has demanded complete secrecy.
所以你一定要
So you're gonna have to
让查尔斯·庞氏和潘金莲离我远点[著名骗子 以庞氏骗局闻名]
keep Charles Ponzi and pussyride away from me.
我们梅耶家人很机智的
We Meyers are very resourceful.
你知道其实你不是我们家人 对吧
You do know you're not really a member of my family, right?
- 知道 - 这就对了
- I do. - Right.
阿斯彭小屋 大卫营
上午 10:20
莫妮卡 你在树上放的
What is that insanity
都是些什么鬼
you're putting all over the tree, Monica?
这是我自制的蔓越莓加爆米花拉花
Oh, this is my homemade cranberry and popcorn tinsel
- 我叫它   - 米花!
- that I like to call - Popcornaments!
看来有人关注我的博客了
Someone's been reading my blog.
我上周才注册了这个词
I just trademarked the word last week.
听起来很可口 又可爱
It sounds delicious and it's adorable.
所以我要叫可口爱
So I'm gonna call it delorable.
看见没 谁不会啊
See? We can all do it.
- 妈妈 - 怎么了
- Hey, Mom. - Yes?
马乔里是生食素食主义者
I just wanted to let you know that Marjorie
受她影响 我也吃素了
is a raw food vegan and she's turned me into one.
她把你影响弯了也影响吃素了 超值套装啊
Oh, so that's two things she's turned you into.
对 所以圣诞晚餐
Yeah, we just thought maybe we could have,
给我们上个素火腿就好了
like, a sham ham for Christmas.
那是什么 亲爱的 像豆腐鸡一样吗
What is that, sweetie? Is that like tofurkey?
不 夫人 豆腐鸡是熟的
No, ma'am, tofurkey is cooked.
素火腿是用生的蘑菇和腌核桃做成的香肠条
This is a raw log made of mushrooms and soaked walnuts.
但是尝起来像火腿?
But it tastes like a ham?
- 对 接近 - 完全不
- Yeah, it's close. - Not at all.
我们可以都减少肉类摄...
We could all cut back on our meat consum...
真对不起 马乔里
I'm terribly sorry, Marjorie.
- 我以为你是赛琳娜  - 没关系 先生
- I thought you were Selina. - That's okay, sir.
人们总是弄错
People make that mistake constantly.
不如我们俩你谁也别碰
How about you touch neither of us?
好吧 我要去核实下那个新潮的点单 然后...
Okay, I'm gonna go check on that funky food order and...
妈妈 我本想问你点事
Mom, I wanted to ask you about something,
但我跟老爸说也行
but I can just talk to Dad about it.
他在财务方面更在行
He's better with money stuff.
什么财务上的事?
What money stuff?
就是我现在钱太多了
Well, it's just that there's so much of it
不知该怎么办
that it's really tough to know what to do with it.
乔治叔叔说
Uncle George was saying
我可以卖棕榈滩的房子
that maybe I should sell the Palm Beach house
这样我就可以付清房地产税了
so that I could pay off the estate taxes.
棕榈滩房? 亲爱的 那是我爹最喜欢的房子
Palm Beach house, honey? That was my daddy's favorite house.
其实现在市场形势大好
Actually, Lee, right now is a fantastic time to sell.
凯瑟琳 你还记得巴西那个连锁酒店吗?
And, Catherine, do you remember that Brazil hotel chain?
- 哈? - 我告诉他们你是素食主义者
- What? - I told them about your veganism
他们决定将整个酒店区改建成生态度假区
and they decided to convert the whole thing to an eco resort.
- 才没呢 - 我包里有协定书
- No, they didn't. - I have a prospectus in my briefcase.
听我说 既然我们在提前庆祝圣诞节
I'll tell you what. I think we should not talk about money
还是最好不要谈钱了
during our sort of pre-Christmas Christmas celebration.
凯瑟琳 马乔里 你们能不能出去
Catherine and Marjorie, can you gals go outside
拿些木柴生个火呀?
and get some wood to start a fire?
女士 你女儿那双炫目的眼睛可以自己生火
Ma'am, your daughter's dazzling eyes can start a fire themselves.
太可怕了
Okay, well, that's terrifying,
但我们确实需要从屋外拿些木柴
but I actually do think we need to get some wood from outside.
- 是 女士 - 谢谢 盖瑞 得走了
- Yes, ma'am. - Thanks. Gary, we got to go.
核桃小屋
上午 10:31
中国人都到了吗?
Okay, are the Chinese here yet?
堵在路上 女士
Delayed on the road, ma'am.
估计开的慢还不用信号灯[亚洲人开车烂 梗]
Presumably driving slowly and not using their signals.
黛博拉莉的产超有消息了吗
Hey, any updates on Debralee's sonogram?
没 我快疯了
Nothing. I'm going crazy.
你干啥呢 猥琐版鲁班?
What do you got going there, Depravey Crockett?
雕刻的终极是心中无物 心随刀舞
You can't go in with a plan. The knife tells you.
好吧 汇报情况吧本
Okay, so lay it on me, Ben.
女士 一切还在商讨前阶段
It's all been prenegotiated, ma'am.
以换取您取消制裁
In exchange for you lifting the sanctions,
中国方面同意在俄亥俄州建立一个电子厂
China's agreed to build an electronics plant in Ohio
并在北卡罗来纳建立发动机装配厂
and an engine assembly plant in North Carolina.
所以我们攻下了北卡罗来纳和俄亥俄州
Okay, so we got North Carolina, Ohio.
这是我身为总统的职责
That's the presidency for me.
一如往常 我们也提出了
And as per usual, we raised the issue
让达赖喇嘛和班禅喇嘛会西藏的议题
of the Dalai Lama and the Panchen Lama returning to Tibet.
- 又是达赖喇 我烦死他了 - 一秒都忍不了他
- Dalai Lama, I'm so sick of him. - He's insufferable.
迈克 新闻稿准备了吗?
Do we have a press release ready to go, Mike?
我只需要按发送 我们就
All I got to do is press send and we
等等 我得先查查拼写
actually, I do need to spell-check this thing.
女士 明娜·哈基宁已过安检 朝这赶来
Ma'am, Minna Hkkinen is through security and headed this way.
她这么个民主党派自闭性冷淡
How is it that that Asperger
是怎么把自己挤进这件事里来的?
salad inserted herself into this situation?
陆主席信任她 喜欢她在国际货币基金组织的表现
President Lu trusts her. Likes what she did with the IMF.
不 我来告诉你他喜欢啥 北欧小穴
No, I'll tell you what he likes. Nordic beav.
真诱人
Irresistible
咋了?
What?
- 明娜 - 赛琳娜
- Oh, Minna! - Selina.
- 你好呀 - 你好哇 上次我们见面
- Hello. - Hello. I have not seen you
还是我选国际货币基金组织头头 你没投票给我那回呢
since you failed to vote for me to be head of the IMF.
新发型啊
And, oh, you changed your hair.
谢谢 我加了些挑染
Thank you, yes. I have more highlights.
新眼皮啊 你整容了眼睛
And you changed your eyelids. You had oculoplasty.
你看着精神了点
You look more alert.
最新民调数据已出
Well, the latest poll numbers are in
乔纳 瑞安竞选总办公室
上午 10:43
你落后寡妇谢尔曼20个点
and you've fallen 20 points behind the Widow Sherman.
我们得让你远离人类
We have to keep you away from people.
在你周围装点些树 让你看上去更像人的尺寸
Yeah, surround you with some trees. Make you look human-sized.
重回你那傻老母捡你的自然栖息地吧
Yeah, back to the natural habitat your nitwit mother
你个剃了毛的傻野人
found you in, you fucking shaved Sasquatch.
但好消息是
But the good news is that you're
你仅落后Jon H Ryan三个点 不管他是谁[乔纳海报设计错误梗]
only three points behind Jon H Ryan, whoever that is.
金发妞什么情况?
Hey, Slick. What's Blondie's situation?
有粉她给口吗?
Does she choke for Coke?
你该问她
You should ask her.
今年挺难熬的
It's been a very hard year.
更年期不太好对付
The menopause has really taken a hold of me.
- 是吗? - 你明白的啊 你也更年期了
- Is that so? Yeah. - Yes. You know-- you're menopausal.
- 什么? - 你也更年期了
- What? - You're menopausal as well.
我才没有
No, I'm not
- 没有? - 咋了?
- No? - What?
不可能 你绝对更年期
No, you are.
不 你比我大 所以我...
No, you're older than me, so I...
其实我比你小两岁
No, I am actually two years younger.
我的姨妈还按时拜访
Oh, I still have regular periods,
但我的关节确实有点浮肿了
but my joints, they're very swollen.
我们还是回到中国的话题上吧
You know, I wonder if we can just get back to the Chinese.
月桂小屋
上午 10:50
中国人可能要改一下谈好的条件
The Chinese may try to change the terms of the done deal.
- 是吗? - 是
- Really? - Yes.
但如果他们真这么做...
But if they do this...
...你要准备好演生气离席
...you are simply ready to perform the walkout
让他们相信你不会再协商了
to convince the Chinese that you will not negotiate
如果合议的条款不尽如人意
if the terms of the deal are not satisfactory.
你就说 这些条款我们不接受
You say the terms are unacceptable
然后你摊开手掌这样
and you take both your palms and you place them
使劲拍桌子
firmly on the table like that.
- 我天 - 然后你就走出去
- Oh, God. - Then you walk out.
然后有个人需要说一句 这是史无前例的
And then someone must say this is unprecedented.
- 她从来没这样过 - 本可以
- She never does this. - Ben can do that.
- 谁? 我? - 实际操作起来比听起来难多了
- Who, me? - It is much harder than it sounds.
- 我们排练一下? - 当然
- Perhaps we should rehearse? - Absolutely.
我们不接受
So this is unacceptable.
然后 我走出去
And then, uh, I walk out.
太假了 再来一遍
No, that is not credible. You try again.
我们无法接受
This is unacceptable.
还是一样 只是响了点
No, you see, that's the same, but it's just louder.
她从来没这样过
She never does this.
这个不错 很真实啊
no, that is good. Now, that is convincing.
- 姑娘们 - 妈妈
Hey, girlies. - Mom.
阿斯彭小屋
上午 11:48
- 亲爱的? - 打开礼物看看吧
- Yes, honey? - I want you to open your gift.
毕竟现在我们提前过圣诞节前夜 我送了你一点东西
Since technically it's early Christmas Eve, I got you something.
是什么呀
What have we got here?
1907年第二次海牙会议上使用过的笔
It was used in 1907 at the Second Hague Convention.
我想等到你被正式当选之后
And I figured you could use it to sign important peace treaties
你可以用它签一些重要的和平协议
when you're officially elected.
太棒了 凯瑟琳
It's actually lovely, Catherine.
证券所给了我一张全黑的金属新卡
Amex gave me this crazy new card that's made out of black metal.
这真的表现了
It truly shows the special
我们母女之间伟大的亲情啊
mommy-daughter bond that you and I share.
- 太棒了 - 我有个主意
- So good. - I have an idea.
马乔里 看看我给你了什么
Marjorie, why don't you open my gift?
你给马乔里准备礼物了
Oh, you got Marjorie a gift.
马乔里现在也是我们家庭中的一分子了嘛 是吧哥们?
Marjorie's part of the family now, aren't you, pal?
我也给马乔里了一份礼物 对吗 盖里?
Yeah, I got Marjorie a gift, too. Um, right, Gary?
- 是的 - 是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- 礼物可漂亮了 - 卡在安保了
- It's beautiful. - Stuck in security.
卡在那了 我不知道怎么回事
Stuck in security. I don't know how that happened.
- 我有快递单号 - 拆礼物吧
- I got the tracking number. - Okay. Let's see what you got.
看 是本旧书
Ah, it's an old book.
- 你喜欢吗? - 我被情感淹没了
- Do you like it? - I am overcome with emotion.
天啊
Oh, my God.
是格特鲁德·斯泰因诗集的第一版
It's a first edition Gertrude Stein.
他是马乔里最喜欢的诗人了
That's Marjorie's favorite poet.
你怎么知道的 爸爸?
How did you know that, Dad?
- 我倾听 - 我要找个特殊的地方珍藏这本书
- I listen. - I'm going to put this someplace special.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hi.
我注意到有两辆坐满亚洲人的高尔夫车开过来了
I noticed two golf carts filled with Asian people.
- 我们得走了 - 那是厨房工作人员
- Yeah, we should go. - That's the kitchen crew and the chef.
- 他们西装革履的 - 是啊
- They wear really nice suits. - Yeah.
- 我想去找给马乔里的礼物了 - 我也是
- Okay, I want to go find Marjorie's gift. - Me, too.
我会先介绍一下对方
So, I will make the introductions.
- 你就穿着这个? - 啥?
- You're wearing that? - What?
这位是陆歧将主席
This is President Lu Chi-Jang...
他学的是化学工程
Studied chemical engineering.
这位是共产党党内秘书长
Secretary General of the Communist Party...
...是中华人民共和国的最高领导者之一
...paramount leader of the People's Republic of China.
- 这位是张胜喜 - 他收集画
- This is Zhang Shengxi. - He collects art.
国务院总理
Premier of the State Council.
他儿子在乔治城大学读大一
His son is a freshman at Georgetown.
这位是肖金东 第一副总理
This is Xao Jintong, 1st Rank Vice Premier...
伦敦大学经济系
London School of Economics.
他最喜欢的零食是冻草莓干
favorite snack is freeze-dried strawberries.
谢谢你 我就听见了个草莓
Thank you. I didn't get any of that except strawberries.
- 好吧 - 交换礼物
- Okay. - The exchanging of gifts.
这是一张中国最受欢迎的卡通人物
This is a depiction of the most popular
做成的剪贴 哭哭猪
children's cartoon character in China, Sad Piglet.
这看起来跟我女儿凯瑟琳一模一样
It looks just like my daughter Catherine.
你女儿是位美丽的女人
Your daughter is a beautiful woman
而这是一只猪啊
and this is a piglet.
- 还是只在哭的猪 - 不不 我很喜欢
- It's upset. - Oh, no, no, no. I-- I love it.
相信我 如果你跟凯瑟琳提海洋世界
Believe me, if you say SeaWorld to Catherine
你就会懂得我的意思了
you will understand what I'm talking about.
这简直太可爱了 太感谢你们了
This is just lovely. Thank you very much.
现在该我们的礼物了
And now our gift.
这是一件来自清朝的丝绸袍
This is a silk robe from the Qing Dynasty.
龙的图案意味着财富
The dragon symbolizes good fortune.
你们太慷慨了 我有些诚惶诚恐啊
Your generosity is overwhelming.
- 下面该我... - 这是...
- And so... - This is...
真的还有啊? 这远远超出我们的想象啊
Seriously? This is beyond what we imagined.
也超出我们的准备
Or prepared for.
这是一条来自清朝的挂毯
This is a tapestry from Qing Dynasty.
中间的图案 牡丹
The central image, the peony,
是忠诚和品德的象征
is a symbol of royalty and virtue.
这简直太美了 而且我希望没有别的礼物了
This is exquisite and I really hope that's all.
现在轮到我们的礼物了
And now our gifts for you.
这是个美国水晶洞
This is an American geode,
象征着我们两国之间
which symbolizes the solid foundation
坚实的友谊基础
that we have between our two countries.
它的闪烁也寄托了
And it sparkles like we hope
我们对两国对话持续闪光的期待
our conversation will sparkle.
谢谢你们的石头
Thank you for this rock.
还有这瓶酒
Um, and this wine
产自加州纳帕谷
from Napa Valley, California.
还有另一瓶酒 也产自一个本地酒庄
And this additional wine, also from a local vineyard
就在... 新西兰
in, uh, New Zealand,
新西兰算是我们的本地
which is local to us
它离亚洲也很近
and it's also close to Asia,
所以它也算你们的本地
which makes it local to you
我们都是老乡啊
as we are all local friends.
- 谢谢 - 她就客气一下
- Thank you. - She's just being polite.
- 陆主席不喝酒 - 天哪
- President Lu does not drink. - Oh, God.
将啊 美国有一句老话
Um, Jang, there's a common saying here in America,
"稍等一下 这还没完"
"But wait, there's more."
所以我为您呈上最后一件礼物
So I would like to present our final gift to you.
一杆充满了历史价值 意义重大的笔
A very meaningful and historic pen
是1907年第二次海牙会议上使用过的笔
from the Second Hague Conference of 1907.
盖瑞 盒子
Gary, the box.
- 真要给? - 是
- What? Really? - Yes.
这是份十分合适的礼物
This is a very worthy gift.
- 太好了 - 充满了历史价值并且很符合文化
- Oh, good. - It is historically significant and apt.
金色对中国来说是很吉祥的颜色
Gold is a very auspicious color for the Chinese.
- 象征了繁荣和好运 - 太棒了
- It signifies prosperity and good luck. - Oh, great.
- 你让他们很满意 - 那我也很满意
- You have pleased them. - Oh, I'm pleased, then. Great.
现在他们在讨论
And now they are
你怎么会穿得这么随便
discussing how casually you are dressed.
他们说你穿得像个犯人
They say you look like a prisoner
或者像个海盗
or a pirate.
还像本练习册
An exercise book.
为什么更年期女王没有提醒我们
Why did Menopause not warn us
核桃小屋
下午 1:45
中国人准备的礼物比我们多这么多?
that the Chinese were going to out gift us like that?
我们的情报显示他们特恨你
Our intel suggested they hated you.
女士 丹和艾米的电话
Ma'am, Dan and Amy for you.
- 怎么了? - 女士 乔纳给自己补了一枪
- What? - Ma'am, Jonah shot himself in the foot.
我天 他又捅什么篓子了?
Oh, my God. What did he do this time?
不是 他是真的朝自己脚上开了一枪 我们在急诊室呢
No, he literally shot himself in the foot. We're in the ER.
看CNN 正在播呢
Turn on CNN, ma'am. It's on right now.
开一下...
Turn on the...
我从前也是在这片树林里和我继父一起打猎
These are the woods where I used to hunt with my stepfather.
他教会了我如何正确...
And he taught me the proper...
卧槽
Jesus!
- 天哪 - 我没事
- Oh, my God. - I'm okay.
候选人瑞安惨遭不幸
天哪
Oh, my God.
- 本 不好笑 - 我知道 太惨了
- It's not funny, Ben. - I know, it's terrible.
- 一点点血嘛 - 到处都是血啊
- A little bit of blood. - You are, it's all over the place.
二年级的时候乔纳玩橡皮筋也射到过眼睛
Jonah shot himself in the eye with a rubber band in second grade.
谢尔曼回应瑞安事件
过去和现在我都是这么告诉他的...
I tell him now what I told him then...
枪支很危险
guns can be dangerous.
我们祈祷他早日康复
We're all praying for his recovery.
直说吧 有多糟?
So lay it on me. How bad is it?
有一系列复杂的骨折 一部分骨头被打裂了
It's a complicated fracture. Shattered some bone.
- 他们说大概要... - 不是说他 对我来说有多糟?
- They say it's gonna take... - No, not for him, for me.
对 情况严峻 但我们还不至于...
Right. Critical condition, but we're not throwing in the...
我听不下去了
Okay, I'm not listening to any more of this.
新罕布什尔是奥布莱恩的了
That's New Hampshire for O'Brien.
- 我们得赶紧拿到中国人答应的那些工厂 - 你好
- We got to have those factories now. - Ni hao.
陆主席请你一起露天散步
President Lu requests to go on a nature walk with you.
我是总统 我才不走路
Well, I'm the president. I don't walk.
他也是总统 他想走路
He is also the president and he likes to walk.
真要走?
On a walk?
大卫营是艾森豪威总统[1953-1961任职]
Camp David is where President Eisenhower came
得了心脏病以后进行修养的地方
to recover after his heart attack.
他现在好点了吗?
Is he okay?
总统艾森... 他去世 他死了 他早已不在了
President Eis-- he's pass-- he's dead. He's long gone.
这条路最早是富兰克林·德兰诺·罗斯福[1933-1945任职]
Now this path was originally used by F.D.R.
用来晨练散步的
For his morning strolls.
或者说晨练滚圈圈的[小罗斯福下肢瘫痪长期使用轮椅]
Or rolls, I should say.
你还有口香糖吗
Uh, do you have more gum?
能蹭你块口香糖吗
Can I bum a piece of gum?
我可以和你一起嚼口香糖吗
Uh, may I chew gum with you?
谢谢 中国口香糖啊
Thank you. Chinese gum, huh?
酷啊 我第一次吃
Pretty cool. Never had it.
哇 好带劲啊
Oh, wow. It's got a kick.
意想不到啊
Who knew?
谢谢 等等
Thank-- oh, hang on.
我有个软件
I have just the thing.
- Gracias[西班牙语谢谢] - 不对 不好意思 语言不对
- Gracias. - Sorry, no, no. Wrong language.
我们需要合作协商
Well, we need to work together
更好的处理朝鲜问题
to better engage with North Korea
因为朝鲜人民也跟我一样 是人
because the North Koreans are people like us.
除了他们没饭吃
Except without any food.
妈 总算找到你了
Hi, Mom. Oh, I'm so happy to see you.
- 不 别翻 - 我只是想说清楚 我和我女朋友
- No, no. - Just to be clear, my girlfriend and I
不只是素食主义者 我们是生素食主义者
aren't just vegan, we're raw vegan
也就是说 不吃肉 蛋 奶
which means no meat, no dairy,
以及所有煮熟的东西
and absolutely nothing cooked at all.
- 谢谢你 - 好的 棒棒哒
- Thank you. - Okay, good.
妈 早点回来啊
Mom, come back soon, okay?
莫妮卡在做肉蔻黄豆做的黄油呢
Monica's making some nutmeg soy butter.
棒极了 谢谢
Oh, how wonderful. Thank you.
歧江啊 那是我女儿
Ah, Jang, that was my daughter
显然她没认出来您是谁
and she obviously did not recognize you.
她对国际政治一无所知
She doesn't understand anything about global politics.
我带家人来这只是为了当掩护
My family is here as a cover story.
别 我没这样... 我没那样...
No, but I didn’t... I didn't do that.
我没有... 我没做那种表情
I'm not... I didn't make that face.
我们接着往这边走吧
Shall we carry on this way?
你能帮我翻一下 "我们需要换个新翻译”吗?
Can you translate "We need to get a new translator"?
- 马文花园[大富翁游戏] - 你要买吗？
- Marvin Gardens. - You want it?
阿斯彭小屋
下午 10:16
小凯 我能借200大富翁币吗
Catherine, can I borrow 200 Monopoly dollars?
大家都醒着啊
Oh, everybody's still awake.
- 回来啦 - 回来了
- Hi. - Hi.
那是你们从安检那拿的给马乔里的礼物吗
Is that Marjorie's gift from security?
是吧
Yes.
女士 您真不用这么客气的
Ma'am, I mean, you really didn't need to.
天呐 太惊艳了
Ma'am, this is stunning.
这个嘛 复古的
Well, it's-- it's vintage.
这丝滑 感觉好像是用...
Feels like it was woven
凯瑟琳柔顺的秀发缝制的 来摸摸
out of Catherine's silken hair. Feel this.
我就觉得你会喜欢这种...
I thought you might enjoy something…
- 天啊 - ...像她头发的东西
- Oh, my God. - ...that was like her hair.
- 太感谢了 - 别客气
- Thank you. Thank you so much. - Oh, you're welcome. Ow.
妈 这美得不可思议啊
Mom, I can't believe that. It's gorgeous.
- 我该洗洗睡了 - 该我了
- I got to go to bed. - It was my turn.
- 晚安 - 安安啦
- Good night. - Good night.
你知道那是政府财产吧?
You know that's government property, right?
- 你刚刚犯了联邦罪啊 - 是真的啊
- You just committed a federal crime. - It's real.
新罕布什尔某旅馆
上午 7:03
- 看看这个 - 天啊 这是你的睡衣吗
- You got to see this. - Jesus, those are your pajamas?
我抑制高潮的时候就想象这身衣服
It's the outfit I picture when I'm trying not to come.
那谁?
Who's that?
朱迪·谢尔曼声称一心一意为了新罕布什尔州
Judy Sherman claims she's for New Hampshire,
朱迪 谢尔曼
真正目的?
- 但她真正的目的是什么? - 这是什么情况?
- but what's her real agenda? - What is this?
你要小心一点 枪支很危险的[新罕布什尔州枪械管理较宽松]
You need to be more careful. Guns can be dangerous.
在大选日
On election day,
朱迪 谢尔曼想抢走我们的枪
不能让她赢
告诉朱迪·谢尔曼 我们要的是自由
tell Judy Sherman you care about freedom.
- 这他妈的是什么情况？ - 到处都是
- What the fuck is going on? - Look, it's everywhere.
朱迪·谢尔曼声称一心一意为了新罕布什尔州
Sherman claims she's for New Hampshire…
我天 快看
Oh, my God. Hey.
NRA 国家步枪协会
全国步枪协会发布的
It's the NRA.
真是圣诞奇迹啊
It's a Christmas miracle.
好吧 我待会处理这事 一会儿见
All right, well, I'm gonna get back to this, so I'll see you later.
核桃小屋
上午 9:34
好的 肯特 猜一下 新罕布什尔州又是我们的了是不是
Okay, Kent, best guess, is New Hampshire back in play?
总统女士 我都不需要用"我猜"这个词儿了
Ma'am, I don't even use the colloquial phrase "I guess."
- 让丹和艾米赶紧过来 - 中国客人准备好了
- Get Dan and Amy right now. - The Chinese are ready.
- 她从来不敲门 - 明娜
- She never knocks. - Uh, Minna,
我正在处理些事情
I am right in the middle of something.
瑟琳娜 还需要我再提醒你
Selina, do I need to remind
中国人对守时这事儿有多敏感吗
you how sensitive the Chinese are to promptness?
既然这样 为啥每次我点的馄饨汤送到的时候都是凉的？
Then why is my wonton soup so cold every time they deliver it?
什么?
What?
明娜 我正在处理一个国际紧急事件
Minna, I'm the middle of an international emergency.
中东的事
Um, it's in the Middle East.
科威特的事 我只能说这么多了
It is in Kuwait and that's all I can say.
- 科威特? - 是的
- Kuwait? - Yes.
这太奇怪了
That is so strange.
因为我和阿米尔·阿里阿巴德
Because Amir Al-Khabat and myself,
在Ins上互相关注了
we follow each other on Instagram.
就在五分钟前 他还发了一张吃沙拉的照片呢
Only five minutes ago, he posted a picture of his dinner salad.
这事儿
Ah, well, it happened
就发生在他刚吃完沙拉那会
right after he had that salad, in fact.
间奏曲一样的紧急事件
Sort of an intermezzo emergency.
- 是丹 - 阿里·伊根
- Oop, I got Dan. - Al-Egan.
对 科威特联络处的大使
Yeah, the ambassador to Kuwait's liaison.
谢谢 丹 祝你平安[穆斯林见面问候语]
Thank you. As-salaam-alaikum, Dan.
- 好吧 我先带他们去走走 - 好的
- Okay, I will take them for a walk. - Yeah.
好的 先这样
Yeah. Okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
所以现在我们爱死步枪协会了
Okay, so now we love the NRA.
梅耶总统和阿里阿巴德首相通完电话马上回来
她在那边 跟她女儿
中国人很不高兴
The Chinese are very upset.
月桂小屋
上午 10:17
他们更改了合约的条款
They have changed the terms of the deal.
- 什么? - 中国要求美国
- What? - The Chinese request the United States
不再反对中国对钓鱼岛提出的主权要求
drop its objections to China's claim of the Diaoyu Islands.
委婉一点说
How do I put this delicately?
中方对近期发生的事件感到非常烦恼
The Chinese were very disturbed by a recent incident.
什么事件?
What? What incident?
你女儿的那件事
With your daughter.
明娜 讲真
Oh, my God. Minna, seriously,
那完全是个无心之失
that was a complete honest mistake.
凯瑟琳只是一时迷失
Catherine was just confused.
但作为妈妈 却没有阻止她
But you are her mother. You did not stop her.
我要怎么阻止她啊? 我只能让她做完啊
How could I have stopped her? I had to let her finish.
你也是个母亲 你有个儿子
You're a mother. You've got a son.
你肯定也这样做过吧
I'm sure you've done it before.
- 你也经历过啊 - 并没有
- You've been in this position. - No, I have not.
这种事在冰岛偶尔会有
This happens occasionally in Iceland,
但在那也纯属意外
but there it's just an accident.
我去 他们从一开始真正想要的是这个
God, this was their real demand from the beginning.
这些岛可不是突然出现的
I mean, those islands didn't come out of nowhere.
事实上 这些岛就是突然出现的
Actually, they did. The Chinese created islands
中国靠在海底沉积物上打桩来创造岛屿...
by piling sediment from under the sea...
总统女士 你不能割给他们这些岛屿
Madam President, you can't give them these islands.
这会动摇整个地区的
It'll destabilize the whole region.
麻烦你再去跟歧将谈谈...
Will you please go and talk to Chi-Jang and try...
我试试 但是我不知道
I will try, but I don't know
他能听进去多少
how much I'm going to be able to get his ear.
但是你要做的就是让他听进去一个词
But what you're gonna need to do is let him get a word in.
你知道吗? 这
Okay, well, you know what? This
让我想起了印度和不丹的谈判
reminds me of negotiations between India and Bhutan.
我就知道会这样
Okay, this is what I'm talking about.
不丹态度强硬
Bhutan was being stubborn.
我得去看看我的另一个舞伴了
So, I've got to go check on my other prom date.
- 不好意思 - 啥事? - 你知道在哪能
- I'm sorry. - Yes? - Do you know where I can get
买到这种超好吃的中国口香糖吗?
any more of this amazing Chinese gum?
- 这是尼古丁口香糖 - 不是吧
- It's nicotine gum. - Oh, no.
与中方会谈
下午 4:47
这也改变不了
Well, that does not change the fact
我们的日本朋友
that our friends in Japan
在钓鱼岛也有主权的事实
still have claims to the Diaoyu Islands.
陆总统坚持你方
President Lu says dropping your objections
不得对任何交易持有异议
must be part of any deal.
我们无法接受
Well, that is unacceptable.
- 无法接受! - 她从来没像这样过
- Unacceptable! - She never does this.
我会冲出去 我这就冲
I mean, I will storm out. Here I go.
没门 无法接受的!
No way. It's unacceptable!
不可能
This is not happening.
坦白讲 她从来没这样过
In all honesty, she's never done this.
我不知道中文怎么说...
但是梅耶总统的女人果子在腐烂[指更年期]
我知道两百万听起来好像很多 宝贝儿
I know two million sounds like a lot, sweetie.
但其实不多 这只是为拯救
It's not. It's a small price to pay
巴西雨林所要付出的小小代价
to save the Brazilian rain forest.
但是你不是要砍掉雨林
But aren't you cutting down
来建度假村吗?
the rain forest in order to build the resort?
这样我们就能好好保存没砍的啦
So we can conserve the rest.
这是良性循环
It's a virtuous cycle.
听起来很有道理呢
Well, I guess that makes sense.
- 嗨 妈妈 - 你两在这儿大老远的干嘛呢?
- Hi, Mom. - What are you guys doing all the way out here?
我们等会再谈吧
We can talk about this later.
我会在你枕头上放些宣传册的
I'll leave the pamphlets on your pillow.
- 谢谢 爸爸 - 亲爱的 待儿会见
- Thanks, Dad. - Darling. Lee.
听我说
Okay, listen to me.
如果你需要钱方面的建议
If you want to get advice or talk about money,
你来找我 好吗?
you can come to me, okay?
我手下可有一整个财政部门呢
I've got the whole Treasury Department.
而且他们 你懂得...
And they're, you know...
好吧 不管怎么说他们之前也辉煌过
they've been better, I realize.
虽然你爸爸爱你 宝贝儿
I mean, Daddy loves you, sweetheart,
但他就是个骗子
but he's a crook.
- 我知道 - 对吧?
- I know. - Right?
- 不好意思 - 我只是觉得我可以...
- Oh, excuse me. - I just thought I could...
我不是有意要打扰你们的亲密时刻的
I don't mean to interrupt an intimate moment,
只是谈判
it's just that there have
取得了重大进展
been seismic developments in the negotiations.
你让中方领导阵脚大乱了
You have really rattled the Chinese leaders.
中方领导?
Chinese leaders?
- 是的 凯瑟琳 - 有没搞错啊 妈妈?
- Yes, Catherine. - Seriously, Mom?
我感觉他就快要动用
I think he is going to use the
那支第二次海牙会议的金笔了呢
gold pen from the Second Hague Convention very soon.
你妈妈给了中方领导一支超棒的钢笔
Your mother has given an amazing pen to the Chinese leaders.
- 是金色的... - 她知道... 她知道那笔长啥样
- It's gold... - She know... she knows about that pen.
你简直糟糕透了
You are so terrible.
- 凯瑟琳 - 别叫我
- Catherine. - No.
- 凯瑟琳 这下好了 - 真是抱歉
- Catherine. Okay. - Sorry.
生她的时候就已经像一场噩梦了
Even labor and delivery with her was a nightmare.
是吗? 为什么?
Oh, yes? Why is that?
你阴道很窄吗?
You have a very narrow vagina?
是紧 在美国我们说紧
Well, tight. In the States we say tight.
中国经济现状比任何人想的都要糟糕
The Chinese economy is in a worse state than anyone realized.
这些制裁真的在削弱中国的经济
These sanctions, they are really crippling them.
而且岐将这个人 他高傲又固执
And Chi-Jang, he is a proud, stubborn man.
中国版的达西先生[《傲慢与偏见》男主为人高傲冷漠]
Like a Chinese Mr. Darcy.
不过也蠢兮兮的 像中国版的宾利先生[《傲慢与偏见》中的角色 有点呆笨]
But stupid also, like a Chinese Mr. Bingley.
我爱《欢乐满人间》
I love "Mary Poppins."
因此 如果美国取消对中国的制裁
So if the United States lifts the sanctions
并有意在接下来的25年
and is prepared to meet their demands for industrial metals
与其在工业金属方面的要求达成一致
for the next 25 years, the Chinese might--
中国方面也许 可能 会就西藏问题进行协商
might be prepared to discuss Tibet.
- 吸什么脏了? - 等等 商讨解放西藏?
- To bet on what? - Wait, to talk about freeing Tibet?
不不 他们准备框架协议的协商
No, they are prepared to discuss a framework for talks
是为了探索民族自治的可行性方案
aimed at a possible path to self-determination.
- 我要成为解放西藏的人了? - 不 并不是解放
- I'm freeing Tibet? - No, no, not free.
这应该跟在香港实行的一国两制差不多
It would likely be one country, two systems similar to Hong Kong.
- 对 没错 - 博诺要操翻自个儿的墨镜了(保罗·大卫·休森 政治歌手戴墨镜为经典造型)
- That's it. - Bono's gonna shit his sunglasses.
这简直是人类登上月球一样的历史性时刻
That is like some man on the moon legacy shit.
我的天啊 我赛琳娜·梅耶尔 解放西藏的女人
My God, Selina Meyer, the woman who freed Tibet.
不... 不是 都说了不是解放
Not... no, really, not free.
那俄亥俄州的工厂怎么办?
What about the factories in Ohio?
在最新一轮投票中 乔纳都遥遥领先
Jonah's ahead in all the latest polls.
去你妹的工厂 凡人 我要解放西藏了
Fuck those factories, man. I'm freeing Tibet.
- 去你妹的! - 讲真 不是解放
- Fuck it! - Really, not freeing.
显然 这对于
It is, of course, tragic
俄亥俄州和北卡罗来纳州的失业者是个不幸的消息
for the unemployed workers of Ohio and North Carolina.
他们应该自己努力上大学的
Well, they should have tried going to college.
担心你们芬兰自己的失业问题吧
Worry about your own unemployment in Finland.
芬兰不存在失业问题
We don't have unemployment in Finland.
各位 那个该死的诺贝尔和平奖要归我了
I'm gonna win a Nobel fucking Peace Prize, you guys.
- 抱歉 你还好吧? - 没事
- Oh, sorry. Are you all right? - It's okay.
西藏将会迎来崭新的未来
And Tibet will have a new future.
- 抱歉 不好意思 嗨 宝贝 - 哈瑞·奎师那[礼赞印度教克利须那神的颂歌]
- Oh, God, sorry, sorry. Excuse me. Hey, babe. - Hare Krishna.
喂 B超做的怎么样?
Hi. How was the ultrasound?
梅耶尔 梅耶尔 赛琳娜·梅耶尔...
Meyer, Meyer, Selina Meyer...
双胞胎? 我的老天
Twins? Oh, my God.
不 我也双倍幸福了
Oh, no, I'm twice as happy now.
此处投票
新罕布什尔州特别选举
上午 8:31
我该投谁?
Hmm, who should I vote for, huh?
我该投谁? 这可教不得
Who should I vote for? You can't teach that.
我希望他会投自己一票
I hope he votes for himself.
不好意思 得再给我张选票
Oh, I'm sorry. I need another ballot.
我只是... 我只是需要再来张选票
I just-- I just need another ballot.
我不想跟你说话
I don't want to talk to you.
我想告诉你个事
I want to tell you something,
但这是机密 不能透露给别人 明白吗?
but it's very confidential, okay?
妈妈要解放西藏了
Mommy is going to free Tibet.
我不在乎
I don't care.
凯瑟琳 拜托 小心肝 还记得你小时候
Catherine, come on, honey, remember when you were little
把"解放西藏"的贴纸
and you had that Free
贴在墙上
Tibet" Sticker and you put it up on the wall
却弄不下来了吗 还记得吗
and we couldn't get it off, remember,
因为把它直接贴在墙纸上了
because you put it on wallpaper inexplicably.
嗨 小猫咪 是我 我能进了吗?
Hey, Kit-Cat. It's me. Can I come in?
你一个人进来
Just you.
- 宝贝 - 好吧
- Hey, baby. - Well, yeah.
月桂小屋
下午 12:03
太棒了
Wonderful.
现在 让我们共同庆祝
And now, let us celebrate
传统圣诞晚宴
with a traditional Christmas feast.
这是个...
This is a...
极具传统文化底蕴的
culturally significant and traditional...
- 自由原木蛋糕 - ...自由原木蛋糕
- Freedom log. - ...freedom log.
我们来切开一起分享吧
Why don't we slice that up for everyone to enjoy?
你知道 我们准备好了要发表声明
You know, we have a statement that is ready for release.
不能发表声明
There will be no statement.
这些议题都太过敏感
These are very delicate issues
不能仓促行事
and cannot be rushed.
对 的确如此
Oh, yes, of course.
我完全能够理解
I understand that completely.
然而 也许像西藏这么重大的议题
Although, perhaps when things are as significant as Tibet,
一不小心就被媒体知道了
things are accidently leaked to the press
这样一来全球都会知道我们的成就
so that the world may know of our accomplishments.
如果同时有传言指出 你在中国黑客攻击美国问题上
It would be very unfortunate if it also leaked
欺骗了全国人民 那可就非常不幸了
that you lied to your country about our hacking of your tweets.
这指责太荒谬了
That is ridiculous.
我们手上有你的邮件作证
We have your emails to prove it.
好吧 那我们等你们发表声明
Okay, well, we can just wait for you guys to release a statement.
明娜
Minna.
麦克林托克先生?
Mr. McLintock?
好消息啊
Good news.
你的领养文件被批准了
Your adoption paper has been approved.
您和您妻子就会迎来一个中国宝贝了
You and your wife soon will have a Chinese baby.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
怎么回事?[天朝监听梗]
What is happening?
再见了 安德鲁
Well, good-bye, Andrew.
如果凯瑟琳有任何关于巴西投资的问题
Catherine has any questions about the Brazil investment,
- 随时可以来找我 - 我倒是有个问题
- always available. - I have a question.
是个真的在巴西的投资吗?
Is it actually an investment in Brazil?
我帮你拿吧
I can take this if you'd like.
- 谢谢你 - 别客气
- Thank you. - Yeah, sure.
- 感谢你做的这一切 女士 - 你太客气了
- Thank you for everything, ma'am. - You're so welcome.
好了 陆战一号10分钟后启程
All right, wheels up in 10 minutes on Marine One.
拿上那个...
Pick up the...
- 你好 凯瑟琳 - 认真的吗?
- Hi, Catherine. - Really?
- 怎么了? - 官方消息
- What? - It's official.
今晚20 寡妇谢尔曼认输了
20 this evening, the Widow Sherman conceded.
卧槽 乔纳赢了?
H.R. Fucknstuf, Jonah won the election?
- 险胜 - 我的天呐!
- It was a small margin. - My god！
不过还是可以视为天启的祥瑞
But still counts as a sign of the apocalypse.
所以乔纳会投票支持我 而我会...
So Jonah's gonna vote for me and I'm...
成为总统!
Gonna be president!
- 我必须给他打电话 - 我打了 给你
- I've got to call him. - I got him. He's right here.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
国会议员瑞安
Congressman Ryan.
你好 总统女士
Hello, Madam President.
- 或者我该叫你同事? - 我不这么觉得
- Or should I call you colleague now? - I wouldn't.
我只希望你知道 我
And I just want to let you know that I,
国会议员乔纳·瑞安
Congressman Jonah Ryan,
会亲自投给你把你
will personally deliver you
送上总统宝座的一票
the vote that delivers you the presidency.
这对我意义重大
That means so much to me.
女士 正好我们还在通电话
Ma'am, while I have you on the phone,
新罕布什尔正在与鸦片成瘾的流行病做斗争...
New Hampshire is struggling with an epidemic of opiate addict...
得了 我不会...
Yeah, I'm not gonna...
- 好样的 把那个放我包里 - 好的
- Good. That goes in my bag. - Yeah.
我可以推选新罕布什尔的任何人
I can elect anyone in New Hampshire.
- 我可以推选个穆斯林的艾滋病毒 - 行了 杰夫
- I can elect a Muslim AIDS virus. - Okay, Jeff.
有史以来最小的自杀背心里
A terrorist fucking AIDS virus
他妈的艾滋病的恐怖分子
in the tiniest suicide vest ever made,
我能让他成为新罕布什尔的州长
I could make it governor of New Hampshire.
行了 杰夫 你喝醉了
Okay, Jeff, you're drunk.
新罕布什尔 新罕布什尔
New Hampshire, New Hampshire.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
我的天呐 这是我的功劳
My God. I did this.
我们刚刚让乔纳选上国会了
We just elected Jonah to Congress.
看看周围 我看见了很多熟悉的
Looking around, I see so many familiar faces of people
支持我相信我的面孔
that supported me and believed in me.
也看见了几个反对我的
And I see a few that didn't.
比如杰西卡·汤姆森
Like Jessica Thompson.
嘿 杰西卡 我看见你了
Hey, Jessica. Jessica, I see you there.
确实 自从高中之后就没见过你了
Yeah, it's been a long time since high school.
我喜欢你的新发型
I like what you did with your hair.
你喜欢我的新生活吗?
Do you like what I did with my life?
吉米·欧康纳 我等了20年 想对你说这句话
Jimmy O'Connor, I've been waiting 20 years to say this to you.
我的天呐 这都是我的错
My God, I did this.
你刚刚让乔纳选上国会了
You just elected Jonah to Congress.
我觉得你才是笨蛋
I think that you are the spaz.
但一路过来
But through it all,
有个人一直相信乔纳·瑞安
there was one person who truly believed in Jonah Ryan
那就是乔纳·瑞安
and that was Jonah Ryan.
这是我的梦想
This is my dream,
如果你足够相信自己
that you can believe in yourself so hard
总有一天你会成为国会议员
that you eventually become a congressman.
谢谢你 新罕布什尔 谢谢你
Thank you, New Hampshire. Thank you.
是的 我们非常激动 谢谢你 议员先生
Yeah, well, we're thrilled. Thank you, Congressman.
乔纳会和其他新人一起宣誓就职
Jonah is gonna be sworn in with the rest of the freshmen.
- 是的 - 妈咪 顺便说一句 我已经决定了
- Yeah. - Mom, I've come to a decision, by the way,
关于棕榈滩的海滨别墅
about the Palm Beach house.
- 好吧 凯瑟琳 听着... - 我要留着它
- Okay, Catherine, listen... - I'm keeping it.
凯瑟琳
Catherine.
我要把它当做被拯救的家畜的避难所
And I'm turning it into a sanctuary for rescued farm animals.
什么?
What?
- 被拯救的家畜 - 我听见了
- Rescued farm animals. - Yeah, I heard her.
我认为这很棒 女士
I think it's inspiring, ma'am.
你要把我父亲的房子
You're taking my daddy's house
当做什么山羊的地中海俱乐部[世界著名的旅游度假机构之一]?
and turning it into some Club Med for goats?
不会只有山羊的
Well, it won't be just goats.
我是说 地方足够
I mean, there's so much property
我们可以收纳各种不同的动物
that we were talking about all different kinds of animals.
可以有鸭子或者...
I mean, you could have ducks or...
- 残疾的马 - 猪
- Lame horses. - Pigs.
- 猪 肥胖的猪 - 鸸鹋
- Pigs. Potbellied pigs. - Emus.
也可以有马
And we could have horses as well.
- 好的 - 我们也可以帮助孔雀
- Okay. - We could have peacocks, too.
- 你可以帮助大羊驼吗? - 当然 我们可以
- Can you do llamas? - Yeah, we could have llamas.
- 大羊驼 - 也许三只腿的羊
- Llamas. - Maybe a three-legged goat.